# Brice Veyna

Tulare, CA 93274

Email: briceveyna@gmail.com | LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/brice-veyna

GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/BriceVeyna">https://github.com/BriceVeyna</a> | Portfolio: <a href="https://briceveyna.github.io/Software-Dev-Portfolio/">https://briceveyna.github.io/Software-Dev-Portfolio/</a>

# **Summary**

Full-stack web developer and mechanical design engineer with a background in and passion for design, fabrication, and programming. B.S. in Mechanical Engineering and Certificate in Geographic Information Systems from California State University, Fresno and Certificate in Full-Stack Software Development from University of California, Berkeley Extension. I have work experience as an on-site consulting mechanical design engineer in a food manufacturing environment. I have additional experience as a CNC machinist in a fast-paced machine shop environment for the agricultural and food processing industries. I also have creative experience in the fine arts, having worked with the lead artist to design and paint dozens of large-scale murals across the western US.

# **Employment**

### DESIGN ENGINEER | APPLIED ENGINEERING, INC. | DEC. 2019 - MAR. 2022

- On-site machine design, including single components through full machine assemblies for production lines and supporting areas, at client's facilities in food manufacturing environment.
- On-call reverse engineering of assemblies and components and rapid prototyping/development of improvements to prevent downtime on production lines.
- Established strong working relationship with (new) client's engineering staff and various plant personnel.

### CNC MACHINIST | DIX MACHINE SHOP | MAY 2018 - NOV. 2019

- Machining using CNC and manual mills and lathes.
- Component design using CAD/CAM software.

#### TRIAL ADMINISTRATOR | VALLEY VETERINARIANS | SEPT. 2019 - NOV. 2019

- Prepare and assist veterinarian in administration of treatments for dairy pharmaceutical trial.
- Record field data, document treatments and observations.

### UNDERGRADUATE RESEARCH ASSISTANT | CSU, FRESNO | 2016 - 2017

- Research existing historical GIS archives and information sources for the Fresno State Geography Department.
- Create prototype online spatial, historical, and social archive for Fresno County.

#### ARTIST | VEYNA DESIGN STUDIOS | 2003 - PRESENT

• Assist Lead Artist to design and paint large murals for cities, businesses and private residences.

## **Technical Skills**

#### **PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES**

• HTML, CSS, SCSS, JavaScript, Python, C, G-code

#### **SOFTWARE**

- Web Development: Node.js, Express.js, GraphQL, Apollo, React, Flask
- Database Management: MySQL, Sequelize, MongoDB, Mongoose, SQLAlchemy
- **Cloud Services:** AWS, Heroku, GitHub Pages

- Data Visualization: D3, ReCharts, Leaflet
- HTML Templating: Handlebars, Jinja2
- CSS Frameworks: Bootstrap, Bulma, Foundation, Material-UI
- Computer Aided Design & Manufacturing: Inventor, SolidWorks, ANSYS, AutoCAD, OneCNC
- Numerical Analysis: MATLAB, Mathematica
- **Geographic Information Systems:** ArcGIS, TerrSet/IDRISI
- Design & Animation: Photoshop, Blender
- Office Tools: Microsoft Word, Excel & PowerPoint; Figma, Prezi

#### **EQUIPMENT**

- Manufacturing: CNC Mill, CNC Router, Manual Mill, Manual Lathe, 3-D Printer
- Testing: Rockwell Hardness Tester, Oscilloscope, Multimeter, Handheld XRF Analyzer
- Inspection: Caliper, Micrometer, Indicator, Bore Gage

# **Projects**

### JOB APPLICATION TRACKER WEB APPLICATION

- Job application tracker web application designed and built as a group of 4 using individual and pair programming practices. Built as a MERN stack application with Apollo GraphQL queries, ReCharts data visualization, and authentication using JWT and Bcrypt.
- GitHub Repository: <a href="https://github.com/BriceVeyna/Hireable-Hippo-Helper">https://github.com/BriceVeyna/Hireable-Hippo-Helper</a>
- Deployed Application: <a href="https://hireablehippohelper.herokuapp.com/">https://hireablehippohelper.herokuapp.com/</a>

#### **COMPANY WEBSITE**

• In the process of designing and implementing new website for Veyna Design Studios, Inc. to replace the existing site that had not been updated in 12 years. Built as a MERN stack website with RESTful routes, Leaflet maps, Stripe payment processing, and authentication using JWT and Bcrypt.

#### **CNC ROUTER TABLE**

• Built, modified and troubleshoot mid-sized kit CNC router table. Used to create wooden bas-relief art, molds, and prototype/limited-production furniture and products.

# **Education**

#### CERTIFICATE | SEPT. 2022 | UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA, BERKELEY EXTENSION

• Boot Camp: Full-Stack Software Development

#### B.S. & CERTIFICATE | MAY 2018 | CALIFORNIA STATE UNIVERSITY, FRESNO

• Major: Mechanical Engineering

• Minor: Geography with Geographic Information Systems (GIS) concentration and certificate